FREDERICK GARCIA

A.R.C Specialist

With a proven track record in talent development and leadership, I bring extensive experience in team-building, performance management, and effective strategies. Prepared to excel in a Support role for Operations, I offer a proactive approach to process improvement, dedication to exceptional customer experiences, and strong communication skills with diverse stakeholders.

Certifications

2023-05 Six Sigma Yellow Belt

2023-10 FullStack Academy (Ongoing - JS / HTML / CSS / React / Linux / AWS / Backend)

Work History

Current

2022-05 - A.R.C Specialist (Lvl 4)

AZA3 Corporate Office, Tempe, Arizona

- Drove program with a projected entitlement of 4% in ticket SLA and 20% in ticket age. Succeeded in improving the baseline by 5% in SLA and 26.8% in ticket age.
- Created 7 SOPs for the A.R.C team with the aim of streamlining requests that impact Operations, reducing costs related to COE's.
- Used Kaizen methodology to identify repetitive tasks, then created customized tools using VBA or JavaScript (Tampermonkey) to reduce ARC's total labor spent on researching and actioning requests by 6%.

2021-11 - Outbound C.F Team Lead (Lvl 4)

AZA3 Corporate Office, Tempe, Arizona

- Managed a team of 6-8 L4 Central Flow Leads, assisting the flow leads and site leadership to ensure the team follows proper Standard Work within the East, Central, and West Coast.
- Provided KPI updates for Operations and corporate management, performed risk assessments and took appropriate actions to maintain 68-73 OB TPH across 6 AR sites.
- Successfully reduced inferred time for Outbound Operations in 2 sites by 6%, maintaining staffing / rate / volume accuracy of up to 98% per period.

Contact

Address

Phoenix, AZ 85004

Phone

(435) 255-2134

E-mail

fredega@amazon.com

Skills

MS Office (VBA, V-Lookup, Pivot Tables, etc)

Excellent

Expert in C.F Software (AF / OSP / SCC / Euler / iGraphs / Grafana / etc)

Excellent

QuickSight / SQL / Minitab - Data Manipulation

Excellent

Team Management, Training and Development

Excellent

Customer service, communication, and interpersonal skills

Excellent

Flexible Schedule, willing to relocate & travel

Excellent

Fluent in English & Spanish



Excellent

2021-08 - Process Assistant (LvI 3) 2023-11

BOI5, Boise, Idaho

- Assisted management with IB/OB operations for a team of 10-50 associates within the Sort Center, improving diverting accuracy by 15% during the launch period.
- Developed Excel tool using VBA to mass-open containers (shuttles) after each full Sort, reducing labor spent every 5 hours opening new containers from 3 labor hours to 20 seconds (-99.99% reduction)
- Developed new 3 hires into L3's and L4's by insisting on working in data-driven improvements to each area.

2020-11 - Non-Inventory Receiver (LvI 3) 2021-08

BO12, Boise, Idaho

- Managed a daily budget of workable hours for a team of 7-12 associates, partnering with Operations to allocate labor as necessary.
- Developed and nurtured long-term business relationships with vendors, fostering collaborative partnerships that enhanced supply chain management and customer satisfaction.
- Communicated with external vendor representatives to resolve issues such as damaged shipments and item shortages, reducing waste on each truckload by 1-2%.
- Took ownership of developing 5x L1 employees into L3's by analyzing current set of skills, then setting attainable goals, developing new skills and documenting the results over time.

2020-07 - IC/QA (Lvl 1) 2020-11

SLC2, Salt Lake City, Utah

- Problem Solver
- Learning Ambassador

2019-11 - OB Packer (Lvl 1) 2020-07

SLC1, Salt Lake City, Utah

- Pack Singles All direct/indirect roles
- AFE All direct/indirect roles
- Non-Inventory Material Handler

Education

High School Diploma

Stansbury High School - Stansbury Park, UT